<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Cairo Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="image">Image</string>
    <string name="info">Info</string>
    <string name="start_surfing">Start Surfing</string>
    <string name="app_desc">Cairo (Arabic: القاهرة‎, pronounced, Al-Qahira) is the capital of Egypt and is one of the top largest cities in the <i>Middle East and Africa</i>. Its metropolitan area, with a population of over 20 million, is the <i>largest in Africa, the Arab world, and the Middle East, and the 15th-largest in the world</i>. Cairo is associated with <b>ancient Egypt</b>, as the famous Giza pyramid complex and the ancient city of Memphis are located in its geographical area. Located near the Nile Delta, Cairo was founded in <b>969 AD</b> by the Fatimid dynasty, but the land composing the present-day city was the site of ancient national capitals whose remnants remain visible in parts of Old Cairo. Cairo has long been a centre of the region\'s political and cultural life, and is titled \"<b>the city of a thousand minarets</b>\" for its preponderance of Islamic architecture. Cairo is considered a World City with a \"<b>Beta +</b>\" classification according to <b>GaWC</b>.
        \nCairo has the oldest and largest <i>film and music industries</i> in the Arab world, as well as <u>the world\'s second-oldest institution of higher learning, Al-Azhar University</u>. Many international media, businesses, and organizations have regional headquarters in the city; the Arab League has had its headquarters in Cairo for most of its existence.</string>

    <array name="titles">
        <item>Pharaonic</item>
        <item>Museum</item>
        <item>Islamic</item>
        <item>Coptic</item>
        <item>Park</item>
        <item>Unclassified</item>
    </array>


    <array name="pharaonic">
        <item>@array/pyramid_of_djoser</item>
        <item>@array/giza_necropolis</item>
        <item>@array/city_of_the_dead</item>
        <item>@array/pharaonic_village</item>
    </array>

    <array name="museums">
        <item>@array/egyptian_museum</item>
        <item>@array/coptic_museum</item>
        <item>@array/museum_of_islamic_art_cairo</item>
        <item>@array/national_museum_of_egyptian_civilization</item>
        <item>@array/egyptian_national_military_museum</item>
        <item>@array/egyptian_geological_museum</item>
    </array>

    <array name="islamic">
        <item>@array/alazhar_mosque</item>
        <item>@array/mosque_of_amr_ibn_alas</item>
        <item>@array/salah_el_din_al_ayouby_citadel</item>
        <item>@array/mosque_of_ibn_tulun</item>
        <item>@array/alhussain_mosque</item>
    </array>

    <array name="coptic">
        <item>@array/the_hanging_church</item>
        <item>@array/church_of_st_george</item>
        <item>@array/saint_marks_coptic_orthodox_cathedral</item>
        <item>@array/saints_sergius_and_bacchus_church</item>
        <item>@array/our_lady_of_fatima_cathedral</item>
    </array>

    <array name="parks">
        <item>@array/alazhar_park</item>
        <item>@array/giza_zoo</item>
        <item>@array/orman_garden</item>
        <item>@array/the_international_park</item>
        <item>@array/el_andalos_park</item>
    </array>

    <array name="unclassified">
        <item>@array/khan_elkhalili</item>
        <item>@array/bab_zuweila</item>
        <item>@array/qasr_el_nil_bridge</item>
        <item>@array/tahrir_square</item>
        <item>@array/sixth_of_october_panorama</item>
        <item>@array/unknown_soldier_memorial</item>
    </array>


    <array name="egyptian_museum">
        <item>@drawable/egyptian_museum</item>
        <item>Egyptian Museum</item>
        <item>The Museum of Egyptian Antiquities, known commonly as the Egyptian Museum or Museum of
            Cairo, in Cairo, Egypt, is home to an extensive collection of ancient Egyptian
            antiquities. It has 120,000 items, with a representative amount on display, the
            remainder in storerooms. Built in 1901 by the Italian construction company
            Garozzo-Zaffarani to a design by the French architect Marcel Dourgnon, the edifice is
            one of the largest museums in the region. As of March 2019, the museum is open to the
            public. In 2020 the museum is due to be superseded by the new Grand Egyptian Museum at
            Giza
        </item>
        <item>4.5</item>
    </array>
    <array name="khan_elkhalili">
        <item>@drawable/khan_el_khalili</item>
        <item>Khan el-Khalili</item>
        <item>Khan el-Khalili is a famous bazaar and souq in the historic center of Cairo, Egypt.
            The bazaar district is one of Cairo\'s main attractions for tourists and Egyptians
            alike.
            It is also home to many Egyptian artisans and workshops involved in the production of
            traditional crafts and souvenirs
        </item>
        <item>4.4</item>
    </array>
    <array name="pyramid_of_djoser">
        <item>@drawable/pyramid_of_djoser</item>
        <item>Pyramid of Djoser</item>
        <item>The Pyramid of Djoser, or Step Pyramid, is an archaeological remain in the Saqqara
            necropolis, Egypt, northwest of the city of Memphis. The 6-tier, 4-sided structure is
            the earliest colossal stone building in Egypt. It was built in the 27th century BC
            during the Third Dynasty for the burial of Pharaoh Djoser by his vizier, Imhotep. The
            pyramid is the central feature of a vast mortuary complex in an enormous courtyard
            surrounded by ceremonial structures and decoration. The pyramid went through several
            revisions and redevelopments of the original plan. The pyramid originally stood 62.5
            metres tall, with a base of 109 m × 121 m and was clad in polished white limestone. The
            step pyramid is considered to be the earliest large-scale cut stone construction,
            although the nearby enclosure of Gisr el-Mudir predates the complex, and the South
            American pyramids at Caral are contemporary. In March 2020, the pyramid was reopened for
            visitors after 14-year restoration
        </item>
        <item>4.7</item>
    </array>
    <array name="giza_necropolis">
        <item>@drawable/giza_necropolis</item>
        <item>Giza Necropolis</item>
        <item>The Giza pyramid complex, also called the Giza Necropolis, is the sight on the Giza
            Plateau in Greater Cairo, Egypt that includes the Great Pyramid of Giza, the Pyramid of
            Khafre, and the Pyramid of Menkaure, along with their associated pyramid complexes and
            the Great Sphinx of Giza. All were built during the Fourth Dynasty of the Old Kingdom of
            Ancient Egypt. The sight also includes several cemeteries and the remains of a workers\'
            village. The sight is at the edges of the Western Desert, approximately 9 km west of the
            Nile River in the city of Giza, and about 13 km southwest of the city centre of Cairo.
            The Great Pyramid and the Pyramid of Khafre are the largest pyramids built in ancient
            Egypt, and they have historically been common as emblems of ancient Egypt in the Western
            imagination. They were popularised in Hellenistic times, when the Great Pyramid was
            listed by Antipater of Sidon as one of the Seven Wonders of the World. It is by far the
            oldest of the ancient Wonders and the only one still in existence
        </item>
        <item>4.6</item>
    </array>
    <array name="salah_el_din_al_ayouby_citadel">
        <item>@drawable/salah_el_din_al_ayouby_citadel</item>
        <item>Salah El Din Al Ayouby Citadel</item>
        <item>The Citadel of Cairo or Citadel of Saladin is a medieval Islamic-era fortification in
            Cairo, Egypt, built by Salah ad-Din and further developed by subsequent Egyptian rulers.
            It was the seat of government in Egypt and the residence of its rulers for nearly 700
            years from the 13th to the 19th centuries. Its location on a promontory of the Mokattam
            hills near the center of Cairo commands a strategic position overlooking the city and
            dominating its skyline. At the time of its construction, it was among the most
            impressive and ambitious military fortification projects of its time. It is now a
            preserved historic sight, including mosques and museums. In addition to the initial
            Ayyubid-era construction begun by Saladin in 1176, the Citadel underwent major
            development during the Mamluk Sultanate that followed, culminating with the construction
            projects of Sultan al-Nasir Muhammad in the 14th century. In the first half of the 19th
            century Muhammad Ali Pasha demolished many of the older buildings and built new palaces
            and monuments all across the sight, giving it much of its present form.
        </item>
        <item>4.5</item>
    </array>
    <array name="the_hanging_church">
        <item>@drawable/the_hanging_church</item>
        <item>The Hanging Church</item>
        <item>Saint Virgin Mary\'s Coptic Orthodox Church, also known as The Hanging Church is one
            of the oldest churches in Egypt and the history of a church on this sight dates to the
            third
            century. It belongs to the Coptic Orthodox Church of Alexandria. The Hanging Church is
            named for its location above a gatehouse of Babylon Fortress, the Roman fortress in
            Coptic Cairo; its nave is suspended over a passage. The church is approached by
            twenty-nine steps; early travelers to Cairo dubbed it \"the Staircase Church\". The land
            surface has risen by some six metres since the Roman period so the Roman tower is mostly
            buried below ground, reducing the visual impact of the church\'s elevated position. The
            entrance from the street is through iron gates under a pointed stone arch. The
            nineteenth-century facade with twin bell towers is then seen beyond a narrow courtyard
            decorated with modern art biblical designs. Up the steps and through the entrance is a
            further small courtyard leading to the eleventh-century outer porch.
        </item>
        <item>4.6</item>
    </array>
    <array name="coptic_museum">
        <item>@drawable/coptic_museum</item>
        <item>Coptic Museum</item>
        <item>The Coptic Museum is a museum in Coptic Cairo, Egypt with the largest collection of
            Egyptian Christian artifacts in the world. It was founded by Marcus Simaika in 1908 to
            house Coptic antiquities. The museum traces the history of Egypt from its beginnings to
            the present day. It was erected on 8,000 square meter land offered by the Coptic
            Orthodox Church of Alexandria, under the guardianship of Pope Cyril V. The Coptic museum
            houses the world\'s most important examples of Coptic art.
        </item>
        <item>4.5</item>
    </array>
    <array name="alazhar_park">
        <item>@drawable/al_azhar_park</item>
        <item>Al-Azhar Park</item>
        <item>Al-Azhar Park is a public park located in Cairo, Egypt. Among several honors, this
            park is listed as one of the world\'s sixty great public spaces by the Project for
            Public
            Spaces. The park was created by the Historic Cities Support Programme of the Aga Khan
            Trust for Culture, an entity of the Aga Khan Development Network. The park, developed at
            a cost in excess of USD $30 million, its money was a gift to Cairo from Agha Khan the
            Sixth, a descendant of a Fatimid Caliph. The park project, a great urbanism initiative,
            included: the development of the park archeology involving a 12th-century Ayyubid wall
            historic building rehabilitation several quality of life improvement initiatives
            requiring skills training, area rehabilitation, microfinance, and support in the areas
            of health and education, among others
        </item>
        <item>4.4</item>
    </array>
    <array name="tahrir_square">
        <item>@drawable/tahrir_square</item>
        <item>Tahrir Square</item>
        <item>Tahrir Square, also known as "Martyr Square", is a major public town square in
            downtown Cairo, Egypt. The square has been the location and focus for political
            demonstrations in Cairo, most notably those that led to the 2011 Egyptian revolution and
            the resignation of President Hosni Mubarak
        </item>
        <item>4.4</item>
    </array>
    <array name="city_of_the_dead">
        <item>@drawable/city_of_the_dead</item>
        <item>City of the Dead</item>
        <item>The City of the Dead, or Cairo Necropolis, also referred to as the Qarafa, is a series
            of vast Islamic-era necropolises and cemeteries on the edges of Historic Cairo, in
            Egypt. They extend to the north and to the south of the Cairo Citadel, below the
            Mokattam Hills and outside the historic city walls, covering an area roughly 4 miles
            long. They are included in the UNESCO World Heritage Site of "Historic Cairo"
        </item>
        <item>3.9</item>
    </array>
    <array name="mosque_of_ibn_tulun">
        <item>@drawable/mosque_of_ibn_tulun</item>
        <item>Mosque of Ibn Tulun</item>
        <item>The Mosque of Ibn Tulun is located in Cairo, Egypt. It is the oldest mosque in Egypt
            and Africa surviving in its full original form, and is the largest mosque in Cairo in
            terms of land area. Since Ibn Tulun is an open space, it brings in a lot of sun and
            shadows. It is built around an open square courtyard which allows natural light to
            travel through. Ibn tulun mosque features Samarra style- its decorations being created
            from carved stucco and wood.This mosque is a popular tourist attraction
        </item>
        <item>4.7</item>
    </array>
    <array name="pharaonic_village">
        <item>@drawable/pharaonic_village</item>
        <item>Pharaonic Village</item>
        <item>Living museum of ancient Egyptian life</item>
        <item>4.2</item>
    </array>
    <array name="alazhar_mosque">
        <item>@drawable/al_azhar_mosque</item>
        <item>Al-Azhar Mosque</item>
        <item>Al-Azhar Mosque, known simply in Egypt as Al-Azhar, is an Egyptian mosque in Islamic
            Cairo. Al-Mu\'izz li-Din Allah of the Fatimid dynasty commissioned its construction for
            the newly established capital city in 970. Its name is usually thought to allude to the
            Islamic prophet Muhammad\'s daughter Fatimah, a revered figure in Islam who was given
            the
            title az-Zahrāʾ. It was the first mosque established in Cairo, a city that has since
            gained the nickname "the City of a Thousand Minarets"
        </item>
        <item>4.8</item>
    </array>
    <array name="saints_sergius_and_bacchus_church">
        <item>@drawable/saints_sergius_and_bacchus_church</item>
        <item>Saints Sergius and Bacchus Church</item>
        <item>Saints Sergius and Bacchus Church, also known as Abu Serga, in Coptic Cairo is one of
            the oldest Coptic churches in Egypt, dating back to the 4th century
        </item>
        <item>4.7</item>
    </array>
    <array name="bab_zuweila">
        <item>@drawable/bab_zuweila</item>
        <item>Bab Zuweila</item>
        <item>Bab Zuweila is one of three remaining gates in the walls of the Old City of Cairo, the
            capital of Egypt. It was also known as Bawabbat al-Mitwali during the Ottoman period,
            and is sometimes spelled Bab Zuwayla. It is considered one of the major landmarks of the
            city and is the last remaining southern gate from the walls of Fatimid Cairo in the 11th
            and 12th century. Its name comes from Bab, meaning "gate", and Zuwayla, the name of an
            ethnic group recruited into the Fatimid army from the town of Zuwayla in the Fezzan.
        </item>
        <item>4.5</item>
    </array>
    <array name="giza_zoo">
        <item>@drawable/giza_zoo</item>
        <item>Giza Zoo</item>
        <item>The Giza Zoo is a zoological garden in Giza, Egypt. It is one of the few green areas
            in the city, and includes Giza\'s largest park. The zoo covers about 80 acres, and is
            home to many endangered species, as well as a selection of endemic fauna. The first to
            be built in the Middle East, rare species have been successfully bred in the zoo -
            including the first California sea lion to be born in the region
        </item>
        <item>3.8</item>
    </array>
    <array name="museum_of_islamic_art_cairo">
        <item>@drawable/museum_of_islamic_art_cairo</item>
        <item>Museum of Islamic Art Cairo</item>
        <item>The Museum of Islamic Art in Cairo, Egypt is considered one of the greatest in the
            world, with its exceptional collection of rare woodwork and plaster artefacts, as well
            as metal, ceramic, glass, crystal, and textile objects of all periods, from all over the
            Islamic world
        </item>
        <item>4.6</item>
    </array>
    <array name="alhussain_mosque">
        <item>@drawable/al_hussain_mosque</item>
        <item>Al-Hussain Mosque</item>
        <item>The-Hussein Mosque is a mosque and mausoleum originally built in 1154, then later
            reconstructed in 1874. The mosque is located in Cairo, Egypt, near the Khan El-Khalili
            bazaar in the area known as Al-Hussain. It is considered to be one of the holiest
            Islamic sights in Egypt and named after Prophet Muhammad\'s grandson, Hussain ibn Ali.
            Some Shia Muslims believe that Hussain\'s head is buried on the grounds of the mosque
            where the mausoleum is located today and considered to be what is left of the Fatimid
            architecture in the building
        </item>
        <item>4.6</item>
    </array>
    <array name="mosque_of_amr_ibn_alas">
        <item>@drawable/mosque_of_amr_ibn_al_as</item>
        <item>Mosque of Amr ibn al-As</item>
        <item>The Mosque of Amr ibn al-As, also called the Mosque of Amr, was originally built in
            641–642 AD, as the center of the newly founded capital of Egypt, Fustat. The original
            structure was the first mosque ever built in Egypt and the whole of Africa. Through the
            twentieth century, it was the fourth largest mosque in the Islamic world. The location
            for the mosque was the sight of the tent of the commander of the Muslim army, general
            Amr
            ibn al-As
        </item>
        <item>4.7</item>
    </array>
    <array name="church_of_st_george">
        <item>@drawable/church_of_st_george</item>
        <item>Church of St. George</item>
        <item>The Church of St. George is a Greek Orthodox church within the Babylon Fortress in
            Coptic Cairo. It is part of the Holy Patriarchal Monastery of St George under the Greek
            Orthodox Patriarchate of Alexandria and all Africa. The church dates back to the 10th
            century. The current structure was rebuilt following a 1904 fire, construction was
            finished in 1909. Since 2009, the monastery\'s hegumen has had the rank of bishop with
            title Bishop Babylonos.
        </item>
        <item>4.8</item>
    </array>
    <array name="orman_garden">
        <item>@drawable/orman_garden</item>
        <item>Orman Garden</item>
        <item>The Orman Garden is one of the most famous Botanical gardens in Egypt. It is located
            at Giza, in Cairo. It dates back to 1875 and the reign of Khedive Isma\'il Pasha who
            established the garden on a larger sight than it presently occupies as part of the
            Palace
            of the Khedive. It became a public botanical garden in 1910/1917 and put under the
            Ministry of Agriculture management
        </item>
        <item>4.2</item>
    </array>
    <array name="qasr_el_nil_bridge">
        <item>@drawable/qasr_el_nil_bridge</item>
        <item>Qasr El Nil Bridge</item>
        <item>The Qasr El Nil Bridge, also commonly spelled Kasr El Nil Bridge, is a historic
            structure dating from 1931 which replaced the first bridge to span the Nile River in
            central Cairo, Egypt. It connects Tahrir Square in downtown Cairo to the modern Cairo
            Opera complex toward the southern end of Gezira Island. At the bridge\'s east and west
            approaches are four famous large bronze lion statues; they are late 19th-century works
            by Henri Alfred Jacquemart, French sculptor and animalier. The newer and wider 6th
            October Bridge parallels its route 0.8 kilometres just to the north
        </item>
        <item>4.5</item>
    </array>
    <array name="national_museum_of_egyptian_civilization">
        <item>@drawable/national_museum_of_egyptian_civilization</item>
        <item>National Museum of Egyptian Civilization</item>
        <item>The National Museum of Egyptian Civilization is a large museum in the ancient city of
            Fustat, now part of Cairo, Egypt. The museum partially opened in February 2017 and will
            display a collection of 50,000 artefacts, presenting Egyptian civilization from
            prehistoric times to the present day
        </item>
        <item>4.4</item>
    </array>
    <array name="the_international_park">
        <item>@drawable/the_international_park</item>
        <item>The International Park</item>
        <item>City park</item>
        <item>4.0</item>
    </array>
    <array name="egyptian_national_military_museum">
        <item>@drawable/egyptian_national_military_museum</item>
        <item>Egyptian National Military Museum</item>
        <item>The Egyptian National Military Museum is the official museum of the Egyptian Army
        </item>
        <item>4.3</item>
    </array>
    <array name="el_andalos_park">
        <item>@drawable/el_andalos_park</item>
        <item>El Andalos park</item>
        <item>Park</item>
        <item>3.9</item>
    </array>
    <array name="sixth_of_october_panorama">
        <item>@drawable/sixth_of_october_panorama</item>
        <item>6th of October Panorama</item>
        <item>The 6th of October War Panorama is a museum and memorial to the 1973 October war,
            located in Heliopolis, Cairo. Constructed over an area of 7.5 feddans, it was
            inaugurated on 5 October 1989 by former Egyptian president Hosni Mubarak. It was built
            as a cylindrical fort-like building molded in Islamic architectural style with partial
            assistance from a group of North Korean architects and is run by the Egyptian National
            Military Museums Department
        </item>
        <item>4.4</item>
    </array>
    <array name="unknown_soldier_memorial">
        <item>@drawable/unknown_soldier_memorial</item>
        <item>Unknown Soldier Memorial</item>
        <item>Many Unknown Soldier Memorials for Egyptian and Arab soldiers were constructed inside
            and outside Egypt. The most famous is the one in Cairo. The Unknown Soldier Memorial in
            Cairo is a pyramid-shaped monument in Nasr City. Its construction was ordered by
            president Anwar Sadat in 1974 in honour of Egyptians and Arabs who lost their lives in
            the 1973 October War. It was inaugurated in October 1975. The sight was also chosen for
            the president\'s tomb after his assassination in October 1981
        </item>
        <item>4.4</item>
    </array>
    <array name="saint_marks_coptic_orthodox_cathedral">
        <item>@drawable/saint_marks_coptic_orthodox_cathedral</item>
        <item>Saint Mark\'s Coptic Orthodox Cathedral</item>
        <item>St. Mark\'s Coptic Orthodox Cathedral is a Coptic church located in the Abbassia
            District in Cairo, Egypt. The cathedral is the Seat of the Coptic Orthodox Pope. It was
            built during the time when Pope Cyril VI of Alexandria was Pope of the Coptic Orthodox
            Church, and was inaugurated by him in 1969. The church is dedicated to St Mark the
            Evangelist, an apostle of Jesus and founder of the Coptic Church. Relics of his life are
            kept inside. It was until 2019 by far the largest cathedral in Africa and the Middle
            East
        </item>
        <item>4.6</item>
    </array>
    <array name="egyptian_geological_museum">
        <item>@drawable/egyptian_geological_museum</item>
        <item>Egyptian Geological Museum</item>
        <item>The Egyptian Geological Museum is a museum in Cairo, Egypt. The museum was established
            in 1904 as part of the Egyptian Geological Survey, which had been started in 1896 under
            the direction of the Khedive Ismail. The museum was the first of its kind in the Middle
            East and the African continent
        </item>
        <item>4.0</item>
    </array>
    <array name="our_lady_of_fatima_cathedral">
        <item>@drawable/our_lady_of_fatima_cathedral</item>
        <item>Our Lady of Fatima Cathedral</item>
        <item>The Cathedral of Our Lady of Fatima or just Chaldean Catholic Cathedral in Cairo is a
            religious building that is affiliated with the Catholic Church and is located in the
            city of Cairo, the capital of the African country of Egypt. It is a temple that follows
            the Chaldean or Eastern Syriac Rite in full communion with the Pope in Rome. It
            functions as the main church of the Diocese or Chaldean Eparchy of Cairo which was
            elevated to its current status in 1980 by Pope John Paul II. Currently seat vacant since
            1993 is also a Catholic basilica by decision of the Holy See
        </item>
        <item>4.2</item>
    </array>

</resources>